a philosopher sometimes will employ
strategies of writing that basically
communicate two messages one message to
the superficial reader and another
message to the far smaller set of slow
thoughtful careful readers and he made
more he put more on the table than
anybody else had done before the methods
of writing that a philosopher in that
situation will use so for example
deliberate contradictions another method
that he mentions is that sometimes you
have an author who repeats himself and
he says like as I said earlier but the
repetition includes a modification of
what was said earlier so if you're
reading carefully you see that he said
one thing first and then something else
later and you're supposed to notice that
if you're the right type of reader and
you're not supposed to notice that if
you're the wrong type of reader in other
words it protects the opinions that are
necessary for the community and it also
subjects them to questioning for the
puppies of the philosophical race as he
put it somewhere for the for the young
men who love to think that is
fascinating that with that context
reading Bronze Age mindset by Bronze Age
pervert I don't know if you've read that
that really puts that book into context
because he I know he's probably say
Strauss Ian and I know that he certainly
and studied the ancient texts quite a
bit but the writing style there was
definitely more than one audience in in
the in the in the way he was writing it
and some of it was intended to push
people away and some of and the rest of
it was the sort of hidden messages for
the people who were really thinking
about it and paying attention to it can
you recommend any books by Biden Strauss
here that actually speaks to this sort
of technique because I'd like to check
that out personally the source book is
called persecution in the art of writing
and that's where he says in general why
this type of writing was needed why it's
a problem and why it hasn't been noticed
until he basically put a light on it and
then he also has a few studies there of
medieval thinkers where he tries to show
you how they did this and how to read
them if you read them
this in mind but persecution in the art
of writing is the main text for that